CAMILLE HANSEN-THEOBALD

New York City, NY

Phone: 916-276-6240 | Email: camilleht@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/camille-hansen-theobald | GitHub: https://github.com/camilleNicoleT

| Portfolio: https://github.com/camilleNicoleT/Portfolio.git

SUMMARY

Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from Columbia University, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, Node.js, React and responsive web design. Known as an inventive problem solver excited to develop intuitive apps, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. With each project, striving to attract the audience with a pleasant user experience. Excited to use these skills as a valuable team-member, at a company with similar values, to build better experiences on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS Libraries: React, jQuery, BootStrap Databases: MongoDB, SQL/sequelize

Apps: PWA

Query languages: GraphQL Environment: NODE.js Frameworks: Express.js,

PROJECTS

INDUBITABLY | https://tranquil-ocean-87497.herokuapp.com | https://github.com/geo-a-mac/indubidubly.git

Summary: Job seeking app based off of skills

Role: Front-End

Tools: Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL/Sequelize

MakiMaku | https://camillenicolet.github.io/MakiMaku/ | https://github.com/camilleNicoleT/MakiMaku.git

Summary: Stay at home date ideas generator

Role: CSS and API logic

Tools: Javascript, CSS, Materialize, Third Party API's

EXPERIENCE

American Musical and Dramatic Academy, New York City — Assistant to Student Affairs and Housing

May 2009 - PRESENT

- ~Help improve communication tracking with students by using StarRez and CampusView web applications.
- ~Coordinate transporting student's belongings during emergency situations
- ~Improve Student R.A. performance by updating training protocol and guiding them throughout the semester
- ~Raise student engagement at Residential events by cultivating a community
 - ~Upgraded passive programming to boost staff/student relationship

United Stations Radio Network, New York City — Writer

December 2016 - PRESENT

- ~Developed new comedic bits each week based on current news topics to engage the listeners
- Created new character monologues that raised interest and brought on more clients.
- Polished an established children's Story Podcast "Detective Dexter"to gain more listeners

Cieri Media, New York City — Producer and Host

December 2014 - August 2016

- Helped build quality video content for the NY Indie Film festival and the Cieri Media Youtube page
- Presented engaging awards ceremonies

•

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: Columbia University, NYC, NY, A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Degree or Certification: AMDA, NYC, NY Musical Theater Performance conservatory.